# Mir Housainee

#### (914) 582-4515 || Fargo, ND || mirhousainee@gmail.com

System Analysts | Business Analyst & Certified Project Management Professional (PMP)

#### **Summary**

Over four years of experience working as a business system analyst with focus in business software and system development. Over five years of experience in IT Project Management, entailing design, planning, development, and analysis of more than five large scale IT and data analytics projects. Resourceful, value-driven and agile project management practitioner.

# **Expertise**

Experienced with HP Quality Center & DocSource Experienced with CMMI Experienced with Java, C#, C++, Python, R, SQL

Experienced with Power BI, Tableau Experienced with BI & Forecasting Experienced with Agile Project Management

#### **Professional Experience**

# Business Systems Analyst, ATOS SE, Fargo, ND Oct 2015 - Present

- Assessed systems' capabilities and identified high-level business requirements
- Translated business and user requirements into functional technical specifications.
- Led knowledge management, reporting and evaluations efforts to ensure concepts and comments are consistently transferred between design documents and development.
- For over 2 projects of various scales, used advanced querying, analytics and visualization tools to analyze complex data sets, aiming to ensure concept-solution fidelity, and client satisfaction
- Employed human centered design processes, used a range of management and analytics techniques to produce and lead formative actions. Boosted customer satisfaction by 25% at Atos tech support center.
- Automated Atos call routing processes; minimized waiting time by 30%.
- Supported the design, testing, and configurations teams in translating requirements and use cases into test conditions.
- Completed project deliverables using Agile standards and Atos Service Delivery Standards.
- Communicated project status and provided timely escalation of issues to the Technology Project Manager.

# IT Administrator, United Nations Jan 2013- Jan 2014

- Maintained UNW's computer systems to ensure all aspects are operating efficiently.
- Completed system installs and upgrades as needed.
- Developed niche service functions to support Projects' data analytics and reporting requirements.
- Assisted in developing customized data management systems and analytic tools. Used a range of tools including Microsoft Visio to outline and improve information flows.
- Oversaw date storage and data retrieval systems

# Program Coordinator, United Nations March 2011- Jan 2013

- Planned, implemented, and closed 11 capacity development and research projects in collaboration with several government ministries and UN Project Management Office.
- Managed and led the research and publication of three surveys & statistical handbooks.
- Planned & managed the review-and-refine processes of 22 National Priority Programs.
- Participated in the development of UN Strategy Plan & Country Program Document.
- Coordinated and facilitated monthly regular meetings attended by more than 50 representatives of foreign embassies, UN agencies, civil societies, and government bodies.

# Project Assistant - US Embassy Afghanistan Jan 2009 - Feb 2011

- Assisted in coordination, design, and development of project database system, and registered more than 40,000 detainees and prisoners.
- Prepared monthly project progress and status reports, and supported development of results-based action plans.
- Coordinated the weekly and monthly project staff meetings.
- Assisted in the overall Management and supervision of CSSP projects in 34 provinces.

#### **Education**

North Dakota State University (NDSU) | **B.S in MIS** | Minor in **Computer Science** – Class of 2019

#### **Skills & Certifications**

Project Management Professional (Certified PMP) 2014 - present
Completed IBM Data Science Courses in collaboration with Coursera
Completed Blockchain Smart Contracts offered by University at Buffalo